人人影視
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
字幕組招新中
請訪問 YYSubs.com
翻譯    哈里不是波特   melanie_je
翻譯    易碎的絕對
翻譯    蘇葵
校對    蘇葵
時間軸    caroline   無關風粵
后期    8T
總監    蘇葵
本片改編自1992-2009年倫敦西南
一系列強奸  性侵和搶劫的警方調查
片中使用了部分化名
并為劇情需要而創作了一些角色和場景
17年
'17 years.
這個人在17年間制造了無法言喻的痛苦的恐懼
'That's how long this man has inflicted untold pain and fear
強加于我們社區中最弱勢的群體
'on the most vulnerable members of our community.'
他以為自己掌控這些街道
He thinks he owns those streets.
就像他掌控他闖入的那些家
Like he owns the homes he breaks into.
出去讓他知道你們才是主人
Go out and show him you do.
尋兇
黑夜狩獵者
第二季  第四集
本季終
我們這里顯示的是所有在你檢測范圍周圍
'What we've got here is all the available cameras
可用的監控攝像頭
'on the edge of your plot.'
他昨晚犯案了
He was out last night.'
三起盜竊
'Three burglaries.'
他肯定還開了車
Yeah, he's got to be in a car as well.
我賭他走了莫頓路  一路開過去
My money's on Morton Way, straight down.
本劇由科林·薩頓和艾德·惠特摩爾構思
基于科林·薩頓的回憶錄
這是在我們的時間范圍內
And that's the only vehicle to go down Morton Way
唯一經過莫頓路的車
in our time frame.
那看起來像個小型面包車
That looks like a small people carrier to me.
對  也許是賽飛利
Yeah, maybe a Zafira.
差這么一點確實令人失望
'Coming so close is disappointing.
我很確定我們會有第二次機會
'I'm certain we'll get a second chance,
但前提是我們保持清醒和專注
'but only if we stay sharp and focused.'
接線員  您需要哪種服務
Operator, which service do you require?
警察  他闖入我家了
Police... He's breaking in!
不好意思  你是說警察嗎
I'm sorry, did you say police?
-他在我家里  -你能藏起來嗎  茜拉
- He's in my house! - 'Is there somewhere you can hide, Sheila?'
-茜拉  怎么了  -警察就要到了
- Sheila? What's happening? - The police are coming!
警察就要到了
The police are coming!
他在那
There he is!
我們從中控臺監控
We're monitoring a CAD from LX,
徒步追蹤一個私闖民宅的嫌犯
a foot chase following a break in
警員1263
在蘭貝斯的一個老婦人家中
at the home of an elderly woman.
武裝警察  LO31號警察行動
MP from Lima Oscar Three One, active.
1263號警察徒步追擊嫌犯
Pc 1-2-6-3, chasing suspect on foot.
-這家伙到底是何方神圣  -他只是個凡人  科林
- Who is this bloke? - He's just a man, Colin.
一個可悲  惡劣  無藥可救的人渣
A sad, sorry, messed-up excuse for a man.
好了  請大家暫停工作  安靜
All right, settle down. Settle down.
謝謝  老大有話要說
Thank you. The guv'nor wants a word.
在與成功失之交臂兩周后  我猜測
Two weeks after coming so close, I suspect,
算了  我知道  因為我聽到你們聊天了
oh, sod that, I know, cos I've heard you,
第十六晚
有些同事認為他已經再次隱匿
some of you reckon he's gone to ground
所以現在的做法是完全徹底的浪費時間
and this is just a big, expensive waste of time.
我們那次失手確實可能嚇得他更加謹慎
OK, the near-miss might've spooked him into packing up,
這點我承認
I concede that.
但我不認為他會停手
But I take a different view.
我覺得這會讓他回到  我們知道他自認為
I think it'll drive him back into operating in the one place
安全的地方
we know he feels safe.
我們的關鍵線索仍然是那輛灰色賽飛利
Our key lead remains the grey Zafira
這一點你們也了然于胸
and I know you all know that
但請大家再從不同角度仔細看一下這輛車
but take another look at these different angles.
將它們刻入腦海
Imprint them on your brain,
這樣你們哪怕在遠距離
so that at a glance, or from a distance,
也能一眼鎖定它
you can clock it.
非常感謝大家
Thank you very much.
-34號  -謝謝  內森
- 34. - Cheers, Nath.
-給你  -謝謝  內森
- There you go. - Thanks, Nath.
-要完好的拿回來...  -你沒事吧  老大
- Bring it back in one piece... - Are you all right, guv?
你在中央3000監控系統也看到了
Well, you've seen it at Central 3000,
午夜之后毫無動靜
after midnight nothing happens.
只有狐貍和一些好奇的貓
Foxes and a few inquisitive cats,
夜里的動態也就如此而已
that's the extent of the action.
我真的很擔心他們會開始打瞌睡
I am genuinely worried they're gonna start nodding off.
-不可能  老大  -或者他們習慣了無事發生
- No way, boss. - Or they get so used to nothing happening
而不會在有情況時候及時發現
they don't clock it when it does.
-我覺得不可能  -怎么不可能
- Well, I just can't see that. - Why not?
第一天晚上  他就在區域內徑直開了過去
Very first night, he drove right through the plot.
當時我們不知道他開一輛賽飛利
We didn't know he drove a Zafira then.
那晚總共才幾輛車開過  五輛嗎
How many vehicles went through that night? Five?
他們最起碼應該看到車牌
They could've at least got a reg!
無意冒犯  長官  但這有些苛刻了
With respect, Sir, that's harsh.
監控點的位置  在漆黑的夜里
Clocking the number plate from an OP
-看清車牌并不容易  -你說的也是  內維爾
- and in the dark isn't exactly easy. - Yeah, you're right, Neville.
我只想在他停手之前抓到他
I just want to get him before they pull the plug on us.
-你覺得能很快做到嗎  -我不知道
- You think that's imminent? - I don't know.
跟我來
Come on.
今晚沒有我們  中央3000監控系統也不會有問題
Central 3000 will manage for one night without us.
3號監控點就位
'OP3 in position.'
44號監控點就位
'OP44 in position.'
32號監控點就位
'OP32 in position.'
27號監控點就位
'OP27 in position.'
我們沒預到會有這么高級別人來現場  長官
We weren't expecting such august company, Sir.
我們不想大肆宣揚  只想來看看你們怎么工作
Oh, well, we don't want any fuss, just want to see how it's done.
-這邊走  -謝謝
- This way. - Thank you.
其實今晚我們少一個監控員
Actually, we're down an OP tonight
-有你們幫忙正好  -晚上好
- it's good to have you. - Evening.
等窗簾拉上后我們會給你們倒杯喝的
We'll bring you a cuppa for when the curtain goes up.
非常感謝
Much appreciated.
如果你們能接管這里
If you can handle things here,
我們就去下一條街那邊的偵查屋
we'll be in a scout hut down the next street.
別擔心  我們不會在執勤時睡著的
Don't worry, we're not sleeping on the job.
午夜過后這里會非常冷
After midnight it gets colder than a witch's tit in here.
17號監控點就...
'OP17 in...'
-20號監控點就位  -收到
- 'OP20 in position.' - Received.
U2著名愛爾蘭搖滾樂隊
你知道U2嗎
Do you know U2?
-那個樂隊嗎  -對
- What, the band? - Yeah.
我當然知道  你以為我有多老
Yeah, course I do. How old d'you think I am?
我小時候超級喜歡他們
I was massively into them as a kid.
我去過他們在溫布利舉辦的《約書亞之樹》巡演
I saw them at Wembley on The Joshua Tree tour.
那張專輯很棒  我應該有一張黑膠版
That's a good album. I got it on vinyl somewhere.
好吧  那你一定知道《射向藍天》這首歌了
Right, so, you know the song, Bullet The Blue Sky?
-對  -我有件T恤上印著這歌的歌詞
- Yeah. - Well, I had this t-shirt with the lyrics printed on it.
就是"我看不到那些戰斗機"那句
You know, "I can see those fighter planes,"
下面印的是一個怒吼女士的圖
over a picture of a woman screaming.
我非常喜歡那件衣服
I was dead pleased with it.
很嚴肅  很有政治意義
You know, it was serious, political.
是啊  好過"弗蘭基說請放松"
Yeah. Not "Frankie says relax".
對  也好過"選擇生活"
Right. Not "Choose life".
但只要我穿那件衣服  我媽媽就會說
But whenever I wore it my mum would go,
"現在你能看到那些戰斗機了嗎  小內"
"Can you see those fighter planes yet, Nev?"
媽媽們就這樣
That's mums for you, you know.
你怎么想起這個了
What made you think of that?
我不知道
Dunno.
就...
Just...
我確實沒見過一架戰斗機  所以也許...
I never did see any fighter planes, so maybe...
你現在也有那種感覺  對嗎
You got that feeling now, have you?
對  我就那種感覺  老大
Yeah. Yeah, I do, guv.
我是說...
I mean...
...如果這樣不起作用  那...之后怎么辦
..if this doesn't work, then... what then?
聽我說
I tell you what.
只要他出現  我們就能抓到他
When he does show up, we've got him.
他只要踏入監控范圍
He sets one foot on the plot
就會被被立刻...
and he'll stick out like a fucking...
所有人員  所有人員注意  6號監控點報告
All units, all units, from OP6, be aware.
有一名男性  徒步從拉維妮婭花園走向莫頓大道
We have a male on foot, Lavinia Gardens towards Morton Avenue.
深色帽衫套頭  暫無更多描述  請待命
Dark hoody worn up, no better description, stand by.
他走進了拉維妮婭花園6號的私人車道
He's entering the driveway of number six Lavinia Gardens.
4號監控點  4號監控點  是否收到
OP4. OP4. Did you receive?
4號監控點收到
'OP4. Received.'
待命  待命  他已經走到房子門前
Stand by, stand by. He's down the side of a house.
行動組待命  隨時準備行動
'Mobiles standing by and ready to deploy.'
我們可以看他怎么動手
We could be watching him work.
別動手  我重復  不要動手  所有人待命
Negative, I repeat, negative, all units are to stand by.
可惡  那是什么  手電筒嗎
Shit. What's that, a torch?
-要行動嗎  老大  -不
- Should we make a move, guv? - No.
不行  如果偽裝暴露  也就毀掉了整個行動
No, if we blow our cover, then we've blown the op.
再等一下  直到確定就是他
Just wait till we're sure it's him.
警報解除  警報解除
Stand down, stand down,
只是一個年輕白人男性回家休息
it's a young white male going home to bed.
-他可真幸福  -6號監控點結束
- 'Lucky bastard.' - OP6 out.
行動組撤退
'Mobiles standing down.'
你沒事吧
You ok?
累得我渾身僵硬
I'm stiff as a board!
真不知道他們怎么每晚堅持下來的
I don't know how they do it night after night.
首先  他們白天會睡覺
They sleep in the day, for one.
你就不能晚點去上班嗎
Can't you go in later?
我要參加一個健康安全匯報會
I've got a Health and Safety briefing.
之前兩場我都缺席  上面提醒我
I missed the last two and it's been suggested from above
我最好關注這個方面
that I might want to start taking an interest.
-否則呢  -我不會讓他們有借口搶走我的任務
- Or what? - I'm not giving them any excuse to take my toys away.
你要是在M25公路上身亡
Well, you get killed on the M25,
他們就是要去參加健康安全匯報會的人了
they'll be the ones who need Health and Safety.
特派代表著領導力強而有力
You know, delegation's a hallmark of strong,
-而不是軟弱無能  -路易絲
- not weak, leadership. - Louise..
你這是把自己往絕路上逼
You're running yourself into the ground.
因為內森不在
Cos Nathan's away.
想在你的工作和生活間
It's possible to care about your job
找到...怎么說  平衡  還是有可能的
and find... I don't know, balance.
-但我不行  -你認真試過嗎
- Not for me. - How hard have you looked?
我就是這樣的人  一旦投入  不計安危
That's the way I am, in for a penny, in for a pound.
我羨慕那些能把工作就留在工作場所的人
I envy people who can leave their work at work.
不  你才不羨慕
No, you don't.
你要遲到了
You're gonna be late.
確實
Yes, I am.
只是  過去這幾周觀察你...
It's watching you these last weeks...
我知道一直很壓抑  緊張  殫精竭慮...
I know it's been frustrating, nerve-wracking, exhausting...
但我不太確定...
I'm just not sure...
我不確定...是只因為要抓住這個人嗎
I'm just not sure... it's just about catching this man.
什么意思
What d'you mean?
我覺得你這么投入這個案子
I think you're going at it this hard
是因為你知道這是最后一次...
because you know it's the last time...
...而這個事實讓你前所未有的害怕
..and you're dreading that more than anything.
就看看你自己
I mean, just look at you.
你整晚在外挨凍
You're out all night in the cold
今早還準備正常上班
and straight back in this morning.
你什么都不想錯過  也不愿浪費時間睡覺
You don't want to miss a thing, or waste time sleeping,
因為你知道退休后心里會有多空虛
cos you know how big a hole that's gonna leave.
我也不怪你  我怎么會怪你呢
And I don't blame you. How could I?
這是你最熟悉的事情  你就是這樣的人
You're in your element, it's just who you are.
我只希望當這些都結束  當你退休...
I just hope when it's over, when you're done...
我們現有的生活能令你滿足  我能令你滿足
that what we have is enough. That I'm enough.
你也能滿足于酒吧小游戲和花園中心
And you can make your peace with pub quizzes and garden centres.
前半句沒問題  后半句不行
Yes to the former, no to the latter.
好吧  你又要拿這事取笑了
Oh, go on, make a joke of it.
-除非被脅迫或者假裝可以  -科林
- Unless under duress or in disguise. - Colin.
你說得對
You're right.
我很害怕接下來要發生什么
I am scared about what's next.
我只知道工作  說真的
The job's all I know and, to be honest,
我都不敢想象退休后是什么樣
I can't even imagine what it's gonna be like.
-好了  我得走了  -但我們會沒事  對嗎
- Right, I'd better go. - We'll be all right, though?
希望如此
I hope so.
我們都準備好了
We are all set.
監控點隨時會報告就位
Observation points will be radioing in any minute.
謝謝  米歇爾
Cheers, Michelle.
第十七晚
你們好  他們提前一天放了我們
All right? They let us go a day early.
真的嗎  為什么  表現好的獎勵嗎
Oh, yeah? What's that, time off for good behaviour?
差不多是這意思  對
Something like that, yeah.
-怎么樣  -還行
- How was it? - Yeah, fine.
但是  你忙了好一陣了
But, erm, you've had a bit of a time of it,
所以我現在放你去休息
so I'm relieving you as of now.
不用  好意我心領了  但是我已經來了...
Oh, no, I appreciate the thought but I'm here now...
我支持他的決定  拜托就趕緊離開
I second that. Do us all a favour and bugger off.
-要來杯咖啡嗎  -好  麻煩你了
- Do you want a coffee? - Yeah, please.
明天也休息吧
Take tomorrow off, too.
是周末了  老大
It's the weekend, guv.
好  行  好吧  那謝謝
Ok. All right. Yeah. OK, cheers.
有什么我需要知道的事嗎
Anything I should know?
怎么說呢  盡管希望越來越渺茫
Er, well, in the increasingly unlikely event
我們似乎都已經沒有犯人可阻止了...
that we should actually need to stop someone...
科林·薩頓  大失所望嗎  我可不相信
Colin Sutton, disillusioned? I don't believe it.
我們一定要注意
It is essential that we do it
逮捕地離監控區域越遠越好
as far away from the plot as possible.
好吧
Ok...?
這樣就算嫌疑人被排除
So that if they are ruled out they
他們也不會知道自己是在哪被盯上的
won't know where they were stopped.
這樣暴露行動和行動地點的可能就會降低
Less chance of the op and its location leaking?
你能回來真的太好了  內森
Nice to have you back, Nathan.
謝謝你  謝謝
Thank you. Thank you.
晚安
Good night
九點鐘方向
Nine o'clock.
那是輛賽飛利嗎  就在雪鐵龍后面
That's a Zafira, right? Behind that red Citroen.
對  那是一輛賽飛利
Yeah, that's a Zafira.
小改款  顏色也符合
Facelifted model and the colour's right, too.
而且過去兩周
And it wasn't parked there
該車沒停在那里或附近任何街道上
or any of the surrounding streets in the last fortnight.
馬上報告
Call it in.
控制中心  控制中心  6號監控點報告
Control, Control from OP6,
我能通報一下嗎
can I give a circulation?
說吧  6號監控點報告
'Go ahead, Six.'
我們發現了輛灰色賽飛利
We have a grey Zafira
朝東停在我們哨點對面的拉維妮婭花園
parked opposite our OP on Lavinia Gardens, facing east.
我們之前從未見過這輛車
We haven't seen it before.
車的顏色和年代都很符合
It's of the right colour and age to be of interest,
所以請各部門記住這一點
so can all units please bear this in mind
以防我們隨后通報該車動向
in case we put it up as moving later?
收到  6號監控點  全體注意  全體注意
All received, OP6. All units, all units, please be aware
有輛灰色沃克斯豪爾賽飛利
there is a grey Vauxhall Zafira
朝東停在拉維妮婭花園
stationary on Lavinia Gardens, facing east.
該車之前從未出現過
It has not been seen previously
如有任何動作  6號監控點會更新消息
and OP6 will update if there is any movement.
控制中心下線
Control out.
一點車牌都看不到嗎
Not even a partial on the reg?
抱歉  視線完全被擋住了
'Sorry, totally blocked from view.'
可以讓人去現場看看嗎
Someone could stretch their legs, get it that way?
不行  不能冒險  待在原地
No. Can't risk it. Stay in position.
明白
Understood.
-你好  親愛的  -你好
- Hello, love. - Hello.
-我以為會給你個驚喜  -任務完成了嗎
- Thought I'd surprise you. - Mission accomplished?
內森提前一天結束課程  他堅持讓我回來
Nathan finished his course a day early. He insisted.
希望你們沒吵得太厲害
Hope you didn't put up too much of a fight?
警衛不得不把我送出大樓
Well, security had to see me out of the building,
但除了那個...
but apart from that...
巴西隊的比賽對你早回來沒有吸引力嗎
And the Brazil game wasn't any kind of incentive?
實際上  我從未想過這個
Hadn't even crossed my mind, actually.
-好吧  -但如果你看  我也看
- Uh-huh - But, er, if you're game, I am.
那就繼續吧
Oh, go on, then.
替我謝謝內森
Tell Nathan thank you.
等等  有位行人從拉維妮婭花園向東走來
Hang on. Got a pedestrian heading east on Lavinia Gardens.
是兩位行人
Make that two pedestrians.
他們看起來正朝賽飛利走去
Looks like they're heading for the Zafira.
不  他們經過它上了旁邊那輛車
No, they've moved past it to an adjacent vehicle.
好吧
Ok.
6號監控點呼叫中央3000監控
Central 3000 from OP6.
我們看到了那輛賽飛利的車牌
We've got a sight of the Zafira's plates.
能在全國警察電腦系統中查詢一下嗎
Can we get a PNC vehicle check, please?
6號監控點  請告訴我你的執行令號碼和位置
OP6, let me have your warrant number and location.
號碼是376422
3-7-6-4-2-2.
在拉維妮婭花園  完畢
And Lavinia Gardens, over.
收到  6號監控點  請說車牌號
Received OP6, go ahead with the index.
車牌是是FRZSOBH
Foxtrot Romeo Zero Six Oscar Bravo Hotel.
應該是輛灰色沃克斯豪爾賽飛利
Should be a grey Vauxhall Zafira.
中央3000監控呼叫6號監控點
OP6 from 3000.
確實是輛灰色沃克斯豪爾賽飛利
Indeed it is a grey Vauxhall Zafira,
沒有丟失或被盜記錄  沒任何報告
no trace lost or stolen, no reports.
最新顯示  車主是珍妮弗·格蘭特
Keeper since new shown as a Jennifer Grant,
車是向"隨心行"計劃租的
leased under the Motability Scheme.
收到  中央3000監控  6號監控點下線
'All received, 3000. OP6 out.'
"隨心行"計劃嗎
Motability Scheme?
全稱是"隨心行"運營有限公司
Motability Operations Ltd to give them their full title -
總部在薩瑟克橋路
based on Southwark Bridge Road.
聽起來不像是我們的人
Doesn't sound like our man.
我們還是看看好的方面吧
'Let's try and look on the bright side.
比賽結果1比0  英格蘭以強勁勢頭結束比賽
'It was only 1-0 and England sort of finished strongly.'
大家都這么說
That's what we all say.
-這是種英勇的嘗試  -他們真令人吃驚
- It was a valiant effort. - They were shocking.
第一  這是場友誼賽
One, it's a friendly,
第二  你大部分時間都在睡覺
two, you slept through most of it...
希望世界杯我們能爭點氣吧
God help us in the World Cup.
第三  那是巴西  1比0還行  很不錯了
Three, it's Brazil, so 1-0 is OK, it's respectable.
幸好不是5比0
Lucky it wasn't 5-0.
-下屆世界杯在哪里  -南非
- Where is the next World Cup? - South Africa.
-要不我們去吧  -說真的嗎
- Why don't we go? - Seriously?
可以讓我們遠離花園中心
Keep us out of the garden centres.
看到一名男性  貌似是黑人
Got what looks like a Black male
正匆忙從拉維妮婭花園走來
coming up from Lavinia Gardens in a hurry.
他上了那輛賽飛利
He's getting in the Zafira.
重復一遍  他上了那輛賽飛利
I repeat, he's getting in the Zafira!
亞當  你是我們距離最近的車  你能跟上嗎
Adam, you're our closest vehicle. Can you follow?
收到  馬上出發
Received. Moving out.
他正驅車沿莫頓大道向北駛去
He's driving away, heading north on Morton Avenue.
明白  現在進入拉維妮婭花園
'Understood. Entering Lavinia Gardens now.'
確保空中支援收能到這個
Make sure aerial support get this,
亞當
賽飛利正在沿莫頓大道向北移動
the Zafira is mobile and heading north on Morton Avenue.
你確定他是從拉維妮婭花園出來的嗎
You're confident he came from Lavinia Gardens?
非常肯定
'Very confident.'
需要有人去街上看看  是否有入室搶劫
Someone needs to check the street for a break-in.
可能有受害者需要我們幫助
Could be a victim needs our help.
20號監控點  我們在拉維妮婭花園的盡頭
OP20, we're at the top end of Lavinia Gardens -
我們去
consider it done.
謝謝  20號監控點  確保通知
Thanks, OP20, make sure you notify
相鄰監控點  讓他們可以覆蓋監控范圍
the adjacent OP so they can cover.
我看到了  嫌疑車輛沿莫頓路向北移動
I have the eye. Suspect vehicle moving north on Morton Way.
他正沿著安伯塞德大道的高架段向北行駛
He's moving north on Ambleside Avenue on the elevated section.
亞當  有輛摩托車會超過你上前仔細看看
Adam, you've got the 4-2 coming past you for a closer look.
摩托車報告控制中心  我已看到目標
'4-2 to Control. I have the target in sight.
保持該位置
'Hold back in this position.
-現在超過去看看  -收到
- 'Heading past for a look now.' - 'Copy that.'
已確認  司機是名黑人男性  沒有乘客
'Confirmed. Driver is an IC three male, no passengers.'
謝謝  收到
Thanks, copy that.
我們什么時候攔下他  長官
'When shall we pull him, Sir?'
老大的意思很明確
'The boss was very clear,
我們在距離監控區域盡可能遠的地方逮捕他
'we pick him up as far from the plot as possible.'
-能再具體些嗎  -好的  3公里
- Can you be more specific? - Yes, two miles.
亞當
我們讓摩托車離開  找人在前面支援你
We're taking 4-2 and giving you advanced backup.
杰夫
現在應該到位了
Should be with you now.
那就交給你了  摩托車離開
'I'll leave it to you, then. 4-2 out.'
小凱  那盞燈
Cath. The light.
警察
Police!
怎么回事  快點  現在一定有3公里了
What the fucking going? Come on. That's got to be two miles now.
該死  他向右轉了  重復一遍  他向右轉了
Oh, shit. He's turned right. Repeat, he's turned right.
我還跟著他
I'm still on him.
好的  我迅速掉頭回去追你
'Yeah, I'll scoot back round and catch you up.'
他轉進一個居民區  現在的計劃是什么  長官
He's turned into a residential area. What's the plan now, Sir?
計劃不變
Plan hasn't changed.
請等待  重復一遍  請等待
Please wait, repeat wait,
直到他駛出監控范圍3公里
until he's two miles off the plot.
有架直升機正跟著你作為后備
You have 9-9 tracking you as a fallback.
中央3000監控  直升機報告
'3000 from 9-9,
可以確認我們已經發現目標車輛
'can confirm we have target vehicle in sight.'
有人嗎  警察  能聽見我嗎
Hello? Police, can you hear me?
有什么最新情況嗎  亞當
Do you have an update, Adam?
我拐入了維瑟姆街  重復一遍  維瑟姆街向東
I've turned onto Witham Street. Repeat, east on Witham Street.
我就在你后面
'I'm back behind you.
我知道那條路  都是住宅
'I know that road, it's all residential.'
聽到了嗎  長官  維瑟姆街都是住宅
You hear that, Sir? Witham Street's all residential.
跟蹤他而不暴露會很難
Gonna be tough to follow him without showing up.
他看上去可能要去另一棟房子作案
By the looks of things he could be off to hit a new house,
我建議我們現在把他攔下來
I say we pull him now.
-我明白了  亞當  -凱茜剛剛打電話了
- I hear you, Adam. - Cathy just called.
你說得對  他闖入了拉維妮婭花園的一間平房
You were right, he broke into a bungalow on Lavinia Gardens.
-有人受傷了嗎  -那房子沒有人住
- Anyone hurt? - Property was unoccupied.
長官
'Sir?'
上  上  上  抓住他
Go, go, go, take him!
收到  準備靠近  我們后方有后援嗎
Received. Gonna move in. Are we covered at the rear?
"確認  有后援"
'Confirmed. We're covered.'
-有什么事嗎  -亞當·斯皮爾警員
- Everything all right? - DC Adam Spier.
-能告訴我您的姓名嗎  先生  -不會是尾氣管吧
- Would you mind telling me your name, sir? - Not the exhaust, is it?
您的姓名
Your name, please.
凱爾文  凱爾文·格蘭特
Kelvin. Kelvin Grant.
請關閉發動機把車鑰匙交給我
OK, can you just turn the engine off and hand me the key?
你有身份證件嗎  凱爾文
You got some ID on you, Kelvin?
對不起  沒有
No, sorry.
好像你那邊有兩張銀行卡啊
Well, it looks like you've got a couple of bank cards down there.
它們就行
They'll do.
-這些上寫的是德爾羅伊...格蘭特  -沒錯
- Well, these say Delroy... Grant. - Sure.
我叫德爾羅伊·格蘭特  但大家都叫我凱爾文
My name's Delroy Grant, but everyone calls me Kelvin.
我應該怎么稱呼你
Well, what should I call you?
德爾羅伊
Delroy.
好吧  德爾羅伊  請你待著別動
OK, Delroy, well, if you can stay where you are for me,
我的同事要檢查一下你的后備箱
my colleague's gonna take a look in your boot.
-是開著的嗎  -開著
- Is it open? - Yeah, it's open.
-你是做什么工作的  德爾羅伊  -我是護工
- What d'you do for work, Delroy? - I'm a carer.
是嘛  挺好
Oh, right. OK.
這么晚你出來干什么
And what are you doing out this late?
我在合作社外面等著想買些煙
I was waiting outside the Co-op to buy some puff,
可那家伙一直沒露面
but the guy never showed.
亞當
Adam.
請你走出車來  德爾羅伊
Would you like to step out of the vehicle, please, Delroy?
德爾羅伊·格蘭特  我以涉嫌
Delroy Grant, I am arresting you
強奸  入室盜竊和猥褻罪逮捕你
on suspicion of rape, burglary and indecent assault.
你有權保持沉默  但詢問過程中
You do not have to say anything, but it may harm your defence
你避而不談的問題都將在后續的庭審中
if you do not mention when questioned
可能會成為對你不利的證據
something which you later rely on in court.
科林·薩頓
Colin Sutton.
科林  我是內森  看起來我們抓住他了
'Colin, it's Nathan. Looks like we've got him.'
操  你逗我吧
Fuck. You're joking?
你真覺得我會在凌晨三點
Do you really think I'd joke about something like that
開這樣的玩笑嗎
at three in the morning?
我想不會  你確定是他嗎
'No, I suppose not. Are you sure it's him?'
這么說吧
Well, put it this way,
我們從他銀灰色的賽飛利上起獲了
we recovered his grey top with black stripes
他那件有黑色條紋的灰色上衣
from his silver-grey facelifted Zafira.
-科爾布里奇路的那段監控嗎  -完全吻合
- The Colbridge Road footage? - 'Perfect match,
加上他后備箱里有根撬棒和一把螺絲刀
'plus he had a crowbar and a screwdriver in the boot.
雖然為時尚早
'It's early days,
但我認為那些撬痕正是后者弄出來的
'but I'd say the latter probably made all those pry marks.'
我的天  他叫什么
Bloody hell! What's his name?
德爾羅伊·伊斯頓·格蘭特
Delroy Easton Grant.
從指揮延續性的角度
From a continuity of command angle,
或許由我繼續指揮到早上會更合理一些...
it probably makes sense for me to carry it on till morning...
很高興那個高級調查官的課程沒有白上
Good to see that SIO course wasn't wasted.
是啊  沒想到這么快我就用上了
'Yeah, didn't think I'd put it to use quite so soon.'
干得漂亮  內森  干得漂亮
This is great work, Nathan, it's great work.
請你替我轉達給大家吧
Please pass that onto the others for me, will you?
嗯  我會的
Yeah. Will do.
-我們八點見  -嗯  回頭見
- I'll see you at eight. - 'Yeah. See you then.'
你和誰講這么久
Who are you kidding?
我們抓住他了
We got him.
我去把水燒上
I'll put the kettle on.
-西蒙·摩根  -我是科林·薩頓
- 'Simon Morgan.' - It's Colin Sutton.
抱歉這么早給你打電話
I'm sorry to call you so early,
但我想親自告訴你
but I wanted you to hear it from me,
看起來我們抓住他了
it looks like we've got him.
西蒙
Simon?
嗯  我還在  老天
'Yeah, I'm still here. Fucking hell.'
對  我也是這么說的
Yeah, that's what I said.
我們位于拉維妮婭花園的一個監控點發現...
One of our OPs on Lavinia Gardens saw...
我這就過來
'I'm on my way in.'
好  等你到了我把情況告訴你
OK, I'll fill you in when you get here.
這位我們老大  薩頓先生
This is the boss, Mr Sutton.
你好  長官
Hello, sir.
真是幸會啊
I'm so pleased to meet you.
你是要擊球還是投球啊
So what are you, batting or bowling?
你不太喜歡板球吧  長官
You're not into cricket, are you, sir?
-喜歡啊  -但你還是不打吧
- Yeah. - But you still don't play?
實際上我打  偶爾打  你呢
I do, as a matter of fact, yeah, occasionally. You?
打  我當然打了  擊球和投球
Yes, yes, of course I do. Bat and bowl.
那真不錯啊  我的膝蓋不允許我投球了
Oh, good for you. My knees won't let me bowl,
但我還能像以往一樣地揮棒
but I can still swing a bat around as well as I ever could.
告訴我  長官
Well, tell me, sir,
你覺得英格蘭在南非的機會怎么樣
what do you think of England's chances in South Africa?
我認為我們可以再加一名快投手
I think we could do with one more fast bowler
但是我覺得我們有很大的機會
but, er, I think we've got a great chance.
沒錯  我一直也這么說
Yeah, man, that's what I've been saying!
長官  得告訴你一下
Just so you're aware, sir,
我妻子患了多發性硬化癥  我是她主要的護工
my wife suffers from MS and I'm her primary carer.
很明顯  這會讓她受驚
Obviously, this'll come as a shock to her.
我想會吧
Yeah, I imagine it will.
我只想確保她會受到照顧
Well, I just want to make sure she's properly taken care of.
-否則我會很擔心  -抱歉打斷一下
- I'll be worried otherwise. - Sorry to interrupt.
格蘭特先生  請您簽署一下DNA取樣好嗎
Mr Grant, could I have your signature for the DNA sample?
現在去錄指紋吧
Prints now, please.
這邊
This way.
-還用老式的方法呢  -對  還是濕定型好用
- Still doing 'em old school? - Oh, yeah. Can't beat a wet set.
請把右手給我
I need your right hand, please.
不明白你為什么要費這個勁
Don't know why you're bothering,
你們知道我總是戴著手套
you know I always wore gloves.
剛剛你說了句很有意思的話啊
That was an interesting comment you made just now
關于總是戴著手套的那句話
about always wearing gloves.
我們能取一個你的簽名嗎
Er, could we get a signature off you,
只是確認你說了那句話
just to confirm you made it?
你今晚是否接觸過
Have you had any contact
任何體弱或年長的人  德爾羅伊
with a vulnerable or an elderly person tonight, Delroy?
沒有一個屁股摔壞了
There's no-one out there with a broken hip
無法拿到電話的人嗎
who can't get to the phone?
沒人需要幫助和注意嗎
No-one in need of help and attention?
我今晚沒見任何人
I haven't visited anyone tonight.
如果你有什么不明白
Very important that you ask
請務必問清楚  德爾羅伊  好嗎
if there's anything you don't understand, Delroy. OK?
-天吶  天吶  天吶  -怎么了  德爾羅伊
- Oh, dear, oh, dear, oh, dear. - What is it, Delroy?
你們最好去調查一下我兒子
You really want to have a look at my son.
你兒子
Your son?
這對我來說很難...非常難
This is hard for me... so hard...
但鑒于這些罪名的嚴重性
..but given the seriousness of the offences,
我希望你們能抓對人
I want to make sure you get the right man.
他的DNA會跟我的一樣  或很類似
His DNA's gonna be the same as mine, or very similar,
外加我們身高一致  而且他住在附近
plus we're the same height, and he lives in the area.
你為什么直到現在才告訴我  德爾羅伊
Why did you wait until now to tell us this, Delroy?
我依然處于受驚狀態
I'm still in a state of shock.
-胡扯  -對  當然是胡扯
- Bullshit. - Yeah, course it's bullshit.
雙胞胎的DNA一樣  但父子不可能
Twins can share DNA, but not fathers and sons.
但他說得對  仍然可能很相似
He's right, though, they can be very similar.
-我們需要查這個嗎  -對  我們得打幾個電話
- We need to jump on this? - Yeah, we need to make some calls.
讓帕特麗夏去查兒子  然后我們取樣
Get Patricia to look the son up and we can get a sample.
-好  立刻去辦  老大  -并告訴她我一起去
- Yeah. Will do, boss. - And tell her I want to be there.
你可沒閑著
You didn't hang about.
-我們確定是他嗎  -我想是的
- We're sure it's him? - Yeah, I think so.
-DNA會確認  -他在系統里嗎
- The DNA will confirm. - Was he in the system?
還不知道  我直接來了這里  恭喜
TBC - I came straight here. Congratulations.
你的大日子  你的案子破了
Your day, your case,
-我只是幫忙跨過了終點線  -謝謝
- I just helped it over the finish line. - Thank you.
-我去看看團隊  -好  我也去
- I'll go check on the team. - Yeah, I'll join you.
-我只想看看他的臉  -當然
- I just wanna see his face. - Sure, yeah.
好吧  所以他在系統里嗎
OK, was he in the system or not?
-很復雜  -他沒開玩笑
- It's complicated. - He's not kidding.
聽完他們解釋后我不得不去躺會
I had to go and have a lie down when they explained it.
-只有你這樣  肯尼  -說吧  內森
- That's just you, Kenny. - Go on, Nath.
99年在布羅姆利有一起盜竊
There's a burglary, back in '99 in Bromley.
地方警察通知了米恩斯泰德團隊
Local police inform the Minstead team,
但他們認為不是米恩斯泰德犯
but they don't think it's Minstead Man.
-不符合標準嗎  -對
- Didn't fit the criteria? - No.
所以布羅姆利就自己調查了
So Bromley go ahead and investigate.
受害者有一個鄰居看到一輛車
Now a neighbour of the victim sees a car
她覺得有些可疑
that she thinks looks suspicious
于是就上報了車牌
and she reports the number.
他們一查發現登記在德爾羅伊·格蘭特名字
They run a trace and it's registered to a Delroy Grant
地址是森林山
at an address in Forest Hill.
他們把他名字輸入全國警察數據庫
They put his name in the PNC.
結果發現有六個名字一樣的人
It IDs six people of that name.
一個在哈克尼  有盜竊犯罪史  也登記了DNA
One in Hackney, had a burglary conviction. DNA on file.
好  那這份樣本和我們的犯罪現場樣本呢
Right. And this sample was compared to our scenes?
他們通知我們說哈克尼的德爾羅伊
They informed us that Hackney Delroy
不是米恩斯泰德犯
wasn't Minstead Man.
-聽著很簡單  -對  只不過不知為何那份結果
- Sounds straightforward. - Yeah, except somehow that result
被登記到了森林山的德爾羅伊檔案名下
became assigned to Forest Hill Delroy's profile
并在我們的系統里建檔了
and a nominal was created on our system.
他們的錯誤成了我們的錯誤
Their mistake became our mistake?
對  而且還沒完
Yeah. And it gets worse.
我們隊里有個警員在去找森林山的德爾羅伊
A DC from our team went to visit Forest Hill Delroy
調查他盜竊案當晚的行蹤
to check his movements on the night of the burglary.
嗯  然后呢
Yeah, and...?
他沒在家  結果也沒再繼續跟進了
He was out and it was never followed up.
-那就是我們抓的德爾羅伊嗎  -對
- And that's the Delroy we just nicked? - Yeah.
轉到右側
Turn to your right.
如果采樣了他的DNA
If his DNA had been taken,
立馬就能鑒定出他是米恩斯泰德犯
he would have instantly been identified as Minstead Man.
天吶
Christ...
從那刻起  德爾羅伊·格蘭特這個人就被排除了
From that moment on, the name Delroy Grant was ruled out.
轉向左側
Turn to your left.
他也沒在取樣名單上嗎
And he wasn't on the swabbing list?
對  因為之前因DNA錯誤被排除了
No, been formally eliminated by DNA.
-所以就算用DNA取樣法你們也抓不住他  -對
- So you'd never have got him that way anyway? - No.
在2001年  德爾羅伊·格蘭特這個名字又出現
In 2001, the name Delroy Grant cropped up again
當時有人撥打熱線  說他是嫌犯
when someone called the hotline pushing him as a suspect.
那是在《犯罪調查》節目播出后
It was after one of those Crimewatch appeals.
但沒有采取任何行動
And the action got binned
因為犯罪數據庫說他測了DNA  被排除了
because HOLMES said he'd been cleared by DNA.
十年前
Ten years ago.
十年
A decade.
自那以后有多少受害者
How many victims since then?
小德爾羅伊·格蘭特
'Delroy Grant Jr?'
請進
Come in.
有人跟你一起住這里嗎  德爾羅伊
Does, er, anyone live here with you, Delroy?
我媽和我哥  什么事
My mum and my brother. What's this about?
你沒惹麻煩  也沒有人去世  不是這類事
You're not in any trouble. No-one's died, it's nothing like that.
但我們有些不太好開口的消息要告訴你
But we do have some difficult news to share with you.
好
Ok...
聽著  能坐下嗎
Look, can we sit down?
你聽說過黑夜狩獵者的案子嗎  德爾羅伊
Are you familiar with the Night Stalker case, Delroy?
-聽說過  襲擊老婦人的家伙  -對
- Yeah, the bloke attacking old ladies? - That's right.
新聞上說你們逮捕了一個人
Said on the news you arrested someone.
是的  沒錯
We have, that's correct.
我很遺憾地通知你
I'm very sorry to tell you that
被逮捕的人是你父親  德爾羅伊·伊斯頓·格蘭特
that man is your father, Delroy Easton Grant.
不
No.
不可能  絕對不是
No way. It can't be.
你們
How...
你們有多確認
How sure are you?
我們還沒有百分百的確認
Well, we don't have absolute confirmation yet,
但如果沒有極大把握  我們也不會來這里
but we wouldn't be here unless we were very sure.
你跟你父親多久見一次
How often do you see your dad?
偶爾吧
Now and then.
我們有很長一段時間與他沒有來往
For a long time we had nothing to do with him.
"我們"
"We"?
我  我媽  我哥
Me, Mum, my brother...
為什么
Why was that?
他在我還是小嬰兒時棄我們而去  我想是兩歲
Well, he walked out when I was a toddler. Two, I think.
對
Yeah.
直到我8還是9歲才再次見到他
Didn't see him again till I was eight or nine.
有一天突然出現在學校門外
Turned up at the school gates one day
答應要周末帶我和我哥去游泳
and promised to take me and my brother swimming at the weekend.
媽媽不太樂意  但她看我們這么期待
Mum wasn't keen, but she saw how excited we were
就改變了主意
and changed her mind.
我高興壞了
I was giddy.
就像...圣誕節早晨的孩子
Like a... kid on Christmas morning.
我很早就收拾好了的東西
Had my bags packed hours before
比他預定來接我的時間提前好幾個小時
he was supposed to pick me up.
我記得自己很想向他展示我的后空翻
I remember I really wanted to show him my backflip.
真可悲
Pathetic, really...
但他沒來嗎
But he never turned up?
我一直沒再見到他  直到我二十多歲  而且
I didn't see him again till I was in my 20s and...
那時我已經知道了
by then I knew.
-知道什么  -他對我媽干的事
- Knew...? - What he'd done to Mum.
暴力  毆打
The violence. The beatings.
他讓她經歷的一切
What he'd put her through.
那些可憐的女人
Those poor women...
是誰先聯系誰的  你還是你爸
Who got back in touch, you or your dad?
我
Me.
我和我哥哥
Me and my brother.
有人告訴我們他再婚了
Someone told us that he'd remarried.
他妻子有多發性硬化癥  說他是個完美的丈夫
That his wife had MS and what an amazing husband he was,
是個體貼的看護
what an amazing carer...
-你肯定難以相信吧  -對
- That must've been difficult to believe? - Yeah.
我想著"我得親眼看看"  所以我們去了
"This I have to see," I thought. So we go round.
"好啊  爸  好久不見"
"Hello, Dad. Long time, no see."
都是真的
All true.
他的妻子人很好  但她需要很多照顧
His wife was sweet, but she needed a lot of care...
然后他在那  細心地照顧
and there he was, providing it.
體貼  耐心  井井有條
Kind, patient, everything organised.
我不嫉妒她  我怎么能呢  但我...
I didn't begrudge her, how could I? But...
看著很難受
Hard to see.
我們還要告訴你些其他事  德爾羅伊
Something else we need to tell you, Delroy.
我們完全不相信
We're giving it no credit whatsoever
但你父親稱是你犯下了那些罪行
but your father has accused you of committing these crimes.
-什么  -對
- What...? - Yeah.
就像帕特麗夏說的  我們完全不信
As Patricia said, we don't believe it for a minute,
但我們必須通過DNA測試排除你
but, er, we will have to eliminate you with a DNA test.
抱歉  等等  他說.
Sorry, hang on, he said...
強奸和那一切  他說都是我干的
The rapes and everything? He said it was me?
他為什么要這么說
Why would he say that?
因為他就是這種人
Because that's the sort of person he is,
而且從你剛才告訴我們的來看  他一直是
and, from what you're telling us, always was.
-給你  -謝謝
- There you go. - Thanks.
他們沒有鱷梨泥  我給你買了火腿芝士
They didn't have any torn avocado, I got you ham and cheese.
給
There you go.
我奶奶92歲了依然染發  所剩無幾的頭發
My nan's 92 and still dyes her hair... what's left of it.
她說當你變老后  似乎就失去了身份
She said when you get old it's like you lose your identity.
人們看不見你  只看到一個老人
People don't see you, they just see an old person -
白頭發  淺色大衣  老花鏡  羊群中的一只
grey hair, fawn coat, bad glasses, a sheep in a flock.
所以這案子這么久都沒破  隱形的受害者
That's why this went on so long. Victims were invisible.
對  但我們其他人卻不承認
Yeah, and the rest of us are in denial.
我們都認為不會發生在自己身上
We all think it won't happen to us.
我們能逆勢而行
We'll buck the trend.
便盆  假牙
Bedpans, false teeth,
癡呆  助行架  不可能  不必了  我們不會
dementia, Zimmer frame. No way, no thanks. Not us, mate.
而我們助長謊言的方式是忽略他們
And the way we feed that lie is to ignore them.
我們注意到他們  但卻視而不見
I mean, we notice them, but we don't see them.
我們不會避開視線  但也絕不會多看一眼
We don't avert our gaze, but we certainly don't linger
因為他們是我們不想要卻逃不過的未來
cos they're the future we don't want and can't escape.
對  就像我們在責備他們一般  對吧
Yeah. It's like we blame them, innit.
沒錯
Exactly.
這說明了我們是怎么樣的人
And what the fuck does that say about us?
你還好嗎
You ok?
你說當這一切結束  會給我重創
You said when this was over it would hit me.
是的  我說過  來吧
Yeah, I did. Come on.
-好消息嗎  -DNA結果剛出來
- Good news? - Just got the DNA back -
既成事實  與我們的所有樣本都百分百匹配
effectively 100% match with all our samples.
強奸案的精液
Semen from the rapes,
哈尼斯街受害者面部的口水
saliva from the cheek of the Harness Street victim,
-科爾布里奇路的橙汁盒  -"既成事實"
- the orange juice carton at Colbridge Road... - "Effectively"?
他們是這樣措辭的
Well, they word it like this,
"德爾羅伊·格蘭特的DNA
"The DNA taken from Delroy Grant
與其他人相比  有47.5的10的24次方倍幾率
"is 47.5 septillion times more likely to be linked to the DNA
與米恩斯泰德犯相關"
"of Minstead Man than an unrelated person."
"10的24次方"  我喜歡這說法
"Septillion." I like the sound of that.
-那螺絲刀的痕跡呢  -絕對是他的  老大
- What about the screwdriver marks? - Definitely his, boss.
因為我們在搜查到DNA的兩個現場看到了
As they're present at two of the scenes where we got DNA
還有其他沒有DNA的現場也有
and loads of scenes where we didn't,
這將他與其他數起案件聯系在一起
it links him to literally dozens of offences.
已經告知他這一切了嗎
Has he been confronted with this?
我們開始砸證據后  他就一言不發
No commented as soon as we started rolling.
皇家檢察署給了我們時間
CPS have given us a slot.
我覺得應該盡可能多的起訴他
I say we charge him with as much as possible,
別管什么"反正他肯定要坐牢了"
never mind "He's going down already."
我同意  我們要為盡量多的受害者伸張正義
Agreed. We get justice for as many victims as we can.
我們從嚴處置他吧
Let's throw the fucking book at him.
你理解今天對你提起的這些指控嗎
Do you understand the charges brought against you today?
-我理解  -你怎么辯護
- Yeah, I do. - And how do you plead?
無罪
Not guilty.
格蘭特先生  你被起訴犯下22起罪行
Mr Grant, you are charged with 22 offences
格林威奇地方法庭
而且都是重罪
of the utmost gravity,
五起強奸罪  六起猥褻罪
five of rape, six indecent assaults,
和11起盜竊罪
and 11 burglaries.
盡管你拒絕認罪
Notwithstanding that you deny them,
但在我們看來  如果被判有罪
there is, in our opinion, a very high likelihood
你很有可能會被判很長的牢獄之刑
that, if convicted, you may well receive a long prison sentence.
你將還押候審  待在...
You are remanded in custody to...
貝爾瑪什  女士
Belmarsh, Madam.
貝爾瑪什監獄
To HMP Belmarsh.
現在很多警察都過了退休年齡后繼續工作
Plenty of officers working past retirement age now.
但人總有退休的一天
Everybody's got to go sometime, though.
我只是說說
Just saying.
基爾伯恩的督察已經退休后繼續工作五年了
DI up in Kilburn got his bus pass five years ago.
-五年  -對
- Five years? - Yeah.
前兩天還破了一樁雙殺案
Closed a double murder the other day.
如果你想走  我可以收拾這里
I can finish up here if you want to get off.
不不  你回去吧
No, no. You're all right.
-你確定嗎  -嗯
- You sure? - Yeah.
-好  -內森
- Right. - Nathan?
謝謝
Thanks.
你接受了我  當其他人都不怎么情愿的時候
You let me in when, er, the others weren't so inclined.
我很感激
I appreciate it.
謝天謝地我這么做了  老大
Thank fuck I did, boss.
2011年3月德爾羅伊·格蘭特被判在17年間
總共29項罪名成立  包括強奸和性侵
他被判最低二十七年監禁
本劇為紀念他的所有受害者